Olly Marsters

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CLICK ON THIS LINK TO VIEW THE WEB AND MOBILE VERSION OF THIS DOCUMENT

+44 7592 047792 📞

olly.marsters@yahoo.co.uk 🔀

https://github.com/O-Marsters-1997



Linkedln.com/in/olly-marsters in

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

Python Javascript

HTML CSS

SASS Bootstrap

React Git Node Flask

SQL PostgreSQL

MongoDB Express

Linux Bash

ADDITIONAL

Problem solving Agile methodologies

Research Public Speaking

Communication French

Attention to detail (conversational)

EDUCATION

MA INTERNATIONAL

REALTIONS: 2:1

University of Edinburgh 2015–2020

LEVEL 8 PROFESSIONAL SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

AWARD

Code Clan 2021-2022

A LEVELS:

Brighton College

Latin (A) Politics (A) Philosophy (A) 2013-2015

GCSES:

Hampton School

6A*s (including Maths, Physics, Chemistry) 4As 2012-2013

INTERESTS









PROFILE

A junior software developer with extensive experience in front and back-end technologies. Looking to apply my problem-solving skills and a meticulous attention to detail within a commercial software development environment. Have developed strong interpersonal and time-management skills, through over 6 years experience in customer facing roles. Informed by my background in studying political science, passionate about the potential digital skills have for transformationally impacting the world around us.

TECHNICAL QUALIFICATIONS

CODE CLAN

Code Clan is Scotland's first digital bootcamp. The skills it teaches over a 16 week period enabling its students to transition into the technology sector.

PROJECTS

Flask Cricket World Cup App

ngithub.com/O-Marsters-1997/Flask_cricket_app

Python, Flask, Jinja, PostgreSQL, HTML, SCSS

- · Created an application for keeping track of the 2021 Cricket World Cup.
- Manipulated relavant data using Python and connected that data to the front-end using Flask and Jinja.
- · Managed realtional databases using PostgreSQL.

BBC Sleigh Ride Group Project

ogithub.com/heathercking/BBCSleighRide

Javascript, React, Node, Express, MongoDB, HTML, CSS

- Created an educational app about how Christmas is celbrated around the world, targeted at 4-8 year olds.
- Project management and task allocation, collaborative work through, git branches, library implementation using documentation, non-relational databse maintenace and server construction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT TECHNICIAN

TURING TRUST | JAN 2021-JUN 2021

 Wiping hard-drives, installation of software onto second-hand computers, to be repurposed and sent to schools in Malawi.

IT PROJECTS COORDIANTOR

PROJECT HOPE WEST BANK | JUL 2018 - SEP 2018

- Teaching refugees and local residents basic computer skills.
- · Helping local businesses with social media needs and managing their digital content.

BARTENDER

DINE EDIBNBURGH | OCT 2018-JAN 2020

EVENT STAFF

OFF TO WORK | JUN 2017 - JUL 2021